Yingrui "Rayna" Ji

(530) 204-8288 ♦ raji@ucdavis.edu ♦ San Francisco, CA ♦ linkedin.com/in/raynaji ♦ raynaji.github.io

PROFILE

Master of Science in Business Analytics candidate at UC Davis. 3+ years experiences in analytics and BI using SQL and Tableau for actionable business insights. 3+ years of experience in machine learning using Python and R.

Specialties: Data Visualization, Machine Learning, NLP, Regex, A/B Testing, Web Scraping, Data Management

Tools & Technologies: Microsoft Office, Tableau, Terradata, Trello, Access, MongoDB, SPSS, Github, AWS, GCP, Stata

Programming Languages: SQL, Python, R, VBA, Java, SAS, HTML

Certifications: Tableau Desktop Certified Associate; AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

EDUCATION

University of California, Davis

San Francisco, CA

Master of Science, Business Analytics

Aug. 2019 - Jun. 2020

Highlighted coursework: Experimental Design and Analysis, Advanced Statistics, Machine Learning, Big Data Analytics

Shanghai University of Finance and Economics (SUFE)

Shanghai, CHN

Bachelor of Management, Information Management and Information System

Sept. 2015 - Jun. 2019

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Asian Art Museum (AAM)

San Francisco, CA

Business Analyst & CSM (Customer Success Manager), Practicum Project Team

Sept. 2019 - Present

As part of the UC Davis MSBA, assisting AAM staff in planning exhibition schedules to maximize attendance. Providing consultancy and writing diagnosis reports on their performance and opportunities to increase engagement with client base.

- Ensuring AAM to achieve goals by nailing down and synchronizing handover expectations from both ends as CSM.
- Laying out a roadmap for flagship exhibitions design by performing feature engineering and identifying key attendance-drivers through exploratory data analysis and treatment effect causality analysis via R and Tableau.
- Developing statistical methodology and employing time series model to reconstruct missing data (from 2003-2016) by testing on available daily data (from 2017-2019) in excel and R with an accuracy of 97%.
- Forecasting museum attendance by building a predictive model using Time Series and Random Forests via Python so as to provide guidance on better scheduling exhibitions and planning resources.
- Designing a SQL database to facilitate data validation, storage and analysis for better data management.

eBay Co., Ltd. Shanghai, CHN

Data Analyst Intern, Business Management Department

Jun. 2018 - Jan. 2019

Analyzed data to support decision-making in highly critical business functions like targeted marketing, defect monitoring, etc.

- Designed and created an integrative and interactive dashboard for defect-metrics monitor and preventative analysis.
- Worked cross-functionally to refine SpeedPAK shipping policy guidelines by understanding requirements, conducting
 impact analysis on downstream special users via SQL and communicating results to non-technical.
- Reduced analysis time by 70% by standardization and automation of routine data-pipelines tasks via VBA.
- Researched and identified profitable categories for clients as new market entry by cross-dimensionally analyzing and visualizing millions of transaction data via optimized SQL queries and comparison charts in Excel.

Victoria's Secret Shanghai, CHN

Assistant to Merchandising Manager, Department of Merchandise Planning & Allocating

Sept. 2017 - Dec. 2017

- Spearheaded a project with IT colleges to migrate over to a SQL database; reduced 90% of data search time.
- Led a pilot project in duty-free airport store from A/B testing experiment design ideation to commercialization.
- Employed exploratory and predictive analysis on key KPIs to decide optimal supply quantity and promotion plans.

ADDITIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

Leadership:

Community Student Leader, DSAC (<u>Directors' Student Advisory Council</u>)
Chairman, Student Union of Shanghai University of Finance and Economics
Vice President Education (VPF), SUFF Toastmaster International Club

Sept. 2019 - Present Jun. 2017 - Jun. 2018

Vice President Education (VPE), SUFE Toastmaster International Club

Oct. 2015 - Jun. 2019

Projects:

Topic Modeling and Sentiment Analysis on New York Times articles about 2020 Democratic Primary election (NLP in Python) Check out more projects at <u>my personal website</u>.